Summary

A motivated professional with one year of Software development experience in JavaScript. AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner looking for new opportunities as a Software Developer. Have hands-on experience in developing applications using JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, and React. Searching for a challenging position as a Software Engineer to utilize my tech and design skills for software program development.

Skills

- JavaScript
- React.js
- Typescript
- Node.js

- AWS
- REST API
- MySQL/MongoDB
- Photoshop
- HTML5 / CSS3
- Python
- Java
- Bootstrap
- Quick Learner
- Communication
- Agile/Scrum

Education

• Post Graduation in Web Design and Development Conestoga College, Kitchener, Ontario, Canada.

Bachelor's in Information Technology
Gujarat Technological University, Gujarat, India.

May 2021 – Aug 2022

Jul 2016 - Aug 2020

Certificates

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Dec 2022

- Foundational understanding of AWS Cloud concepts, services, and terminology.
- Knowledge of configuring security groups, virtual private cloud, and cloud storage using S3, Ec2, and DNS service using Route 53.

Work Experience

Customer Experience Associate / Cashier

Aug 2021 – Present

Walmart Canada, Waterloo, Canada

- Provides a positive customer experience with fair, friendly, and courteous service.
- Maintains a safe and clean working environment by complying with procedures, rules, and regulations.
- Answer customer questions and help them with their needs.
- Contributes to team effort by accomplishing related results as needed.

Freelancer Aug 2019 – Present

Remote

- Constructing tasks in accordance with established guidelines.
- Enhancing assignments' accuracy and presentation by editing them.
- The submission of finished assignments in the required format.
- Created Projects based on Front-end and Back-end development using JavaScript, React, WordPress, HTML5, CSS3, Node.js, and python.

Reyaa Technologies, Ahmedabad, India

- Managed Web applications end-to-end, optimizing all cross-browser and implemented procedures for ongoing Website versions.
- Developed Web applications from front to backend using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, Bootstrap, MySQL, and MongoDB.
- Followed SDLC best practices within an Agile environment to produce rapid iterations for clients.
- Integrated object-oriented design and development techniques into projects to support usability goals.

Projects

Vintage Value:

An E-Commerce site for vintage items was created using Full Stack Technologies and implemented Stripe API to securely collect user payment. Used React.js, Node.js, Next.js, JavaScript, and Stripe API.

- Distributed workload with teammates in accordance with sprint plans that were used for the project.
- Daily scrum meetings with the scrum master where daily work is presented, and suggestions are constantly solicited.
- Checks written code for compliance with industry standards and device compatibility.
- Uses web applications, scripts, and programming languages including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and APIs to carry out assignments.
- Has a working knowledge of user interface, cross-browser interoperability, and fundamental web standards.

Health Care Website:

A responsive website created specifically for the client who wants to showcase his medical products on an actual website and give users more knowledge about products and compare it.

- Maintains a professional understanding of web development by tracking trends and participating in study groups.
- collaborating with team members to decide on the website's layout, content, and appearance.
- Observe and maintain the functionality of websites.
- Create a responsive and compatible website to reach the most users possible.

Volunteer and Youth Activity

Yogi Devine Society (YDS) - Canada

Jul 2021- Present

I am a member of the Canadian Yogi Devine Society. This group assists new students with a variety of tasks, including finding housing. I engage in a variety of activities, such as assisting recent immigrants in finding part-time employment and giving accurate information on using public transportation, meeting basic needs, and managing money.